I went viral last month.
One for being right, one for being wrong.
It was quite interesting to see how nice the Reddit community can be.
We looked after Opus 4.7 came out.
We wanted to understand how it performed when you provided context to it,
and some of our early findings in assessing nine models across 11 Node.js
agent skills was that actually, if you take a smaller model
from Anthropic, which is much more viable from a cost perspective
with the right context, it just performed just about the same.
Good evening.
I'm really grateful that all of you guys came out on a Thursday,
when you could have probably a beer or two.
So before I just kick off the presentation,
I'd love to get a sense of the room because I think it will alter
the way I present this.
So first of all, can I get a show of hands?
Who is a software engineer?
Okay.
Who is an engineering manager?
Engineer? Engineering manager.
Okay.
And anybody above that, VP or...
Okay. Gotcha. And out of curiosity,
what are you guys — the other non- engineering folks — doing?
What's sort of like your roles or...
Sorry. I'm a founder.
Founder?
Pretty cool title, and data scientist.
Okay. Gotcha. Cool. Nice.
A show of hands of who has played with agent skills.
Nice. Okay.
And just...
This is for my own curiosity.
Can I get Claude folks?
Can I get Codex?
Interesting.
Okay. And Gemini.
Yeah. Yeah.
Cool.
Okay. So.
We will work.
All right.
So I went viral last month.
One for being right, one for being wrong.
And it was quite interesting to see how nice
the Reddit community can be.
Now also, in contrast, some people mentioned
things that resonated with some of the things I was talking about.
Now, not to keep this too long.
What we were trying to do — a colleague and I —
we looked at what happened after Opus 4.7 came out, the model.
We wanted to understand how it performed when you provided context to it,
and more importantly, how it worked as the frontier
model versus some of — I don't know — its younger siblings.
Younger siblings are not just as good, and some of our early findings
in assessing nine models across 11 Node.js agent skills
was that actually, if you take a smaller model
from Anthropic, which is much more viable from a cost perspective,
with the right context, it just performs just about the same.
And half of the community was ecstatic about that.
The other half, not so much.
But the point of this isn't necessarily to say we're right or wrong.
It's that we touched a nerve.
And my read of
this is that if you touch a nerve, it feels like it's a signal for what
engineers and technical folks are currently thinking about. Now,
I want to make sure that this is clear.
I think what I'm about to say really matters, at least for 2026
and the next couple of years moving forward,
because whether you have not built with agents, you are building with agents,
or you're really at the edge — like the next part of the presentation
hopefully should add some value.
Because here's the thing that we saw from this example: there are four defined
problems we're seeing engineers face when they're developing with agents.
So the first one is we don't really know what good looks like anymore.
And by that, I don't mean necessarily code quality.
I mean practices — how you work from one engineer to another,
from a team to another.
This is still not necessarily clear.
Also, we generate so much code so fast that it's quite common that now
my colleagues and I, we're just deploying code that we don't
even look into anymore — because we are not trying to not bring quality in.
Of course we care about that.
But it's just that some of these models are really getting much better.
But also there's another nagging feeling of like, okay, at some point
things could hit the fan.
How are we dealing with this?
Also, agents are making decisions about reviews.
So this is kind of like the main point I was talking about.
And then the entire question of security is a big question.
So I just want to highlight — so we take a step back.
I think we live in a pretty cool moment.
I'll take the opportunity to present myself very quickly.
My name is Baptiste Fernandez and I don't come from a technical background.
I did economics,
which I think it's pretty cool, but not necessarily an engineering field.
I initially worked for Uber in strategy and then discovered this thing called SQL.
I was like, oh, this is pretty cool.
Then I worked for TikTok in analytics.
So like, then Python, a bit of data science and stuff, and that kind of moved me
now into the field of developer advocacy, where I currently work for Tessl,
which I'll talk to you about in a bit, but why I'm showing this —
I've been an avid tech enthusiast for a long time,
and I would say most of my years contributing probably look like that.
Couple of contributions in open source as of 2026.
I'm almost — I've probably contributed
more in the last three months than my entire life.
Again, not saying that this is necessarily quality, but again, it's signal — like,
as an avid enthusiast, I am able to build and deploy more interesting things.
I like to think it's interesting. Cool.
So the objectives of this talk are threefold.
I want to share what context is and why I think it's coming for you.
It sounds very scary, but it's more like how it's going to benefit you.
I would like to show
you also some common pitfalls that we've looked into in the field.
And finally, I want to share how — like how you should think.
You want to
enable your team to develop with context and how you can upskill your team now.
First point: what is context and what is coming for you?
I'm going to stand on the shoulders of giants here.
I don't know if you recognize his face.
So this is Patrick Debois.
If you've ever heard of this term DevOps, he's the guy that coined the term.
And Patrick has been, you know, at the front edge of DevOps.
This is a handbook he wrote with Gene Kim.
And something that he has been really thinking about is now this entire idea
of the context development lifecycle. By the way, the really cool thing —
Patrick works — I can say Patrick is my colleague.
He's a really fantastic guy.
So this is kind of the new sort
of thinking he's having around the idea of context. So
he advocates — and this is also what our startup believes in.
At the core is the way software engineers are going to be developing
in 2026: first you generate context.
Context can be how libraries should be used, how
you want to go about a certain process, what convention
your small team should follow after generating that context.
You want to —
just like in good old-school
test-driven development, you want to make sure this makes sense.
This is tested in 2026.
This is evaluations, or short term, it's evals.
So how can you eval your context
and how can you evaluate the output of an agent's context?
I'll get a little bit more into detail.
After you are happy with your context,
you've evaluated it.
You want to make sure that other teams are able to benefit from that.
So this is now no longer just you and your small team.
This is across departments.
You know,
these are the conventions
we work with — I don't know — like, we had a talk with Neo4j.
These are the conventions that we go by when we think about security practices
at Neo4j.
And then the last thing is the entire observation.
This is where the lifecycle becomes a bit of a loop.
Did the agent do what we want it to do?
What did it misunderstand?
What did it improvise, or when did it become silent?
And how can we sort of improve that by regenerating that context. So.
The three
takeaways from this: the bottleneck has shifted from code to context.
Context needs its own development lifecycle.
And something interesting is like —
infinite context won't save you.
This is — this is kind of the key thing I like to hammer
home.
Context.
Exactly.
So on the team and enterprise
section, we are thinking of this as like a flywheel.
In fact, this is an image generated by Patrick.
But I think it could also be called the context opportunity,
which is: the context we develop
on our own is then shared within our teams.
And those at some point, depending on the scale of the enterprise,
should also be shared cross-functionally.
And at some point this becomes institutional wisdom.
So — what does that mean?
If there are specific API conventions within your organization,
those can be defined first by an engineering leader.
Once those are clearly explained, policies
and conventions are agreed upon — business decisions have been made.
Then you make sure that this context is evaluated.
You evaluate as well how the agent is leveraging that context
and what it outputs.
You build scenarios around it to make sure that those are working,
and then you can deploy those, and then you can govern those,
and then you make sure the security is in place. So.
To go a tiny bit deeper —
a lot deeper — you can quickly check after this.
So we were at the AI Engineer London a couple of days ago.
So Patrick shared this in more detail.
And again, I think this subject is really resonating — out of all the talks,
this is the one that's really more or less gone viral.
So I think there are a lot of useful nuggets there.
But cool.
All of this was super theoretical.
What does this look like in practice, and how can you benefit
from that?
By the way, does everything make sense so far?
Nice.
So a couple of you have already told me that you're familiar with skills,
but just to bring things back to a level playing field,
this is the official definition by Anthropic, the creators of the skill.
As a sort of markdown file, agent skills are modular capabilities —
like, each skill packages instructions, metadata, and resources
that an agent can then use when relevant.
So who's up for a bit of demo time?
Woo woo.
Thank you.
All right.
So let's make things a little bit more interesting.
So when you — okay.
Let me go here.
So as now
developers in 2026 trying to build with context —
I want, for the sake of argument — what's the
what was this one? I think okay.
This is a skill — data build tool — okay.
It's a pattern about data transformation.
So say John, my colleague, is leveraging the skill
and he's advising that I should use this skill.
So he sends it to me.
And I want to make sure that the skill makes sense.
It's rightly structured.
And I guess this is perhaps the right time to talk about this.
The way
we're currently thinking about testing context and testing the output is twofold.
The first one is the structure of the skill.
Is the skill going to be activated by the agent at the right time when needed?
So this is what we call the reviewing of the skill.
This is: does it perform well against Anthropic best practices as it's written?
That's the first bucket.
The second bucket — and I think what's even more interesting — is when I'm a VP
and I've made this convention about the skill,
I want to make sure that for X, Y, Z scenarios, it is working as I said,
and this is when you generate scenarios upon which you test
whether or not the skill is going to perform as it's asked.
So you pressure test the skill.
So here I'm just going to do the first bucket,
which is: is the skill written well, is it —
is it going to be activated at the right time?
Is it structured and not in a too-dense way?
So the way you do it — and anybody can do this on your own time —
I like Claude — you can use it with Codex — and you just say
can you review this skill with Tessl.
Actually, let me
make sure I'll copy the path.
I'm going to make this
work in the background and I'll show you the UI version of this.
So this.
So the company I work for is Tessl.
I'll just have a brief presentation.
Tessl is a package manager.
We focus on trying to version, evaluate
and provide the entire governance around context, in this case AI skills.
But we believe that context in the age of agents is beyond skills.
But just for the sake of argument, this is skills.
So what I've just done with the agent
working in the background is what you can see in this UI.
So this is the skill that was written by somebody at the Cisco team.
And their skill is to do software security.
So remember how I said there were two evaluations?
The first one is on the structure.
So here — this is what we call the quality.
So the quality has been essentially rated on like three dimensions.
Again, this is against Anthropic best practices.
But how is it in terms of specificity?
Is it complete? Are the trigger terms quality
good enough so that the agent knows to use the skill for the right moment?
So let's see how it's doing in the background. Okay.
So as you can see, Claude has
found the skill,
leveraged Tessl to essentially make the evaluation.
We're seeing things that are working well in terms of like the name —
the lowercase were clear. That's okay.
But what's interesting is the description, which is how a skill gets
activated — that has an opportunity for improvement.
I'll go a little bit more into that in a second.
But the first tip I would give you as you build with context
is: your description, which is your activation
function, is a key thing that most people miss out on.
And as I mentioned, you can therefore spin up
your coding agent to look into that.
Now, I love the terminal, but I feel like it's sometimes
a little bit easier to use a UI, so I'll just get back to this.
So that was kind of like on the structure.
So we can see that for the Cisco security skill,
there are interesting things that can be improved upon — their suggestions.
But the thing that I think is now most interesting is:
is the software security skill from Cisco
working well when we actually give it an evaluation and scenarios to work upon?
So just for the sake of argument here, we said: without context,
or with context — but just imagine it was with skill and without skill here.
What this means is, as the Cisco team is saying,
I would like to make sure that this skill works
very well for, say, I don't know, uses Argon2.
So this is a scenario they've requested, which is: I want to make sure there's
a password hashing that uses the specific
function — in this case, without the skill.
So we use Opus 4.7, by the way.
So with the frontier model, it didn't work well.
What's interesting is with the skill it also didn't work well.
That means the skill has an opportunity for improvement.
But then for some of the others, we can see that for no hard-coded secrets —
interesting
enough, Opus 4.7 doesn't do super well, but with the skill it does work.
So going back
very, very quickly on the terminal side, what I can say is like, okay, cool.
Can you now optimize it with Tessl?
And it's going to go and optimize the skill.
Cool.
That's the end of the short demo.
Now, what does Tessl really do?
So. Tessl now gives —
so our focus is very much on providing this at an enterprise level.
You can do this in public.
Everything I've just done you can use the terminal.
But ultimately we are a product for enterprise folks.
We are a product
where you want to make sure that things are governed in the right way.
Things are provided in private repositories.
A lot of companies — in the end, those contexts will be private.
And so Tessl gives that enterprise spin on how
AI coding agents are used, scaled, and how you improve with context.
So if you know agent enablement is on your roadmap in 2026,
or you want to know how to leverage agents — this is my calendar — feel
free to have a quick chat with me or my email now.
Secondly, one of the objectives is
I wanted to show you some common pitfalls in developing context with agent skills.
So we did a pretty cool
outreach to the open source ecosystem.
I'm a huge fan of the open source ecosystem.
I've learned so much about coding through it,
and so I wanted to reach out to folks and say like, hey,
we have this cool evaluation framework to help you improve your skills.
And so — not to brag — but we've improved quite a lot of skills,
or at least we raised a lot of PRs.
That's all of these PRs.
So we've — we've in total targeted 1,000 repositories.
We've updated almost 10,000 skills in open source.
And it would look something like this.
Like, hey, looked at your repo,
I saw that your performance had a bit of room for improvement.
These are the main things. I'm doing this against the Anthropic best practices.
So again, that first bucket — like, is it structured properly?
Are you writing too much into it? Does it make sense?
Is it duplicative or something else?
And some of them were happy about it.
Some of them actually pushed back in a very healthy way.
So this is a really big maintainer — I think the repo is obra superpower.
It's like an agent skills framework.
And he gave us a lot of very good insights into like,
I don't necessarily agree with the Anthropic approach.
I believe that actually
the static analysis of that first bucket is not enough.
I want to make sure I pressure test the skills,
to which I essentially said like, this is exactly it.
This is why we have this second eval where you can generate
your scenarios and test them against what you actually want.
So another very big signal that I wanted to share
and why this really matters to you —
if you're not already actively doing this, or if you are, you should do it more.
I've done a bit of cold outreach in my life.
Like, before being a bit of an engineer — 40% of people
merge — this is — this is — this is wealth.
Like, just somebody saying like, hey, what's
that conversion?
It's good conversion.
My manager was happy. Yes.
Yes, he was.
So I think this is a signal for you.
Now, what are some of the things that I think — and that I have seen —
my team and I have seen — is first, what I was saying:
a big pitfall when you're developing with context and skills is vague
descriptions. Descriptions are that thing I've highlighted here in green.
And this is, for instance, a bad description, like:
"This is a helpful skill for code review and quality improvement."
Okay, like — is this for Python type of code?
Is this — right underneath we actually show a better one,
which is like, okay, the activation function.
So the description here is: run ESLint with project rules, flag
type, safety violation, etc. etc. etc.
This makes a huge improvement, and that you can do with the Tessl skill review.
Another thing that we've seen
is the god skill, which is a skill that does everything.
Basically, that skill is very often
useless because the agent never knows when to actually activate it,
so it just activates for the wrong reason and then the performance is even worse.
I think this is the one that you probably thought about.
Context bloat.
I've seen some skills where I've had to cut down a thousand lines just because —
super duplicative.
Yeah.
One last thing.
Agent skills are for agents.
I feel like sometimes I've seen — especially in the open source world —
where it was clearly written by a human for a human, but that's the wrong audience.
Like trying to explain what a REST API is or whatnot —
it's just wasted tokens.
And the last one is —
and I think this is where it gets back to what we're saying —
you need a sort of tool to manage
all of this, because skills can vary — it depends which model you're using.
It depends exactly what context it's in.
Like, everything is context dependent.
And this is why every skill is unique.
And every model that activates those skills is like —
they're different from one another.
So if you are an avid Hermes agent person,
then you might want to make sure that it works well for you.
Because I don't know — I'm a Claude fan or whatever.
So I thought those activation rates were pretty insightful. So,
going
down to the third and last part of the talk, which is:
how do you actually enable your team to develop context and upskill?
Now I think there are three main approaches.
Just taking a pulse here.
Does that make sense?
And just —
come again.
Did I say three? Yeah.
Let's see which they are.
Something optimized in terms of — how is that doing?
Good memory.
Let's look at it —
okay.
So it appears that now, after reviewing the skill
and looking into what the optimization should look like, it's now overwritten
the first skill, showing what's changed.
And yeah, without too much surprise,
the front matter has been changed.
I wouldn't be surprised
if there's a bit of reduction as well in terms of sizing.
Yeah.
But maybe —
just maybe — isn't that instead a problem of skills
and language contexts and all that — isn't
that just a problem of
personal
bad judgment in how to put directives to someone else?
If you have a proper system with how-to-dos
and a human should know, and therefore
you already have a base to make a skill, or you can word it differently for an agent.
But if the system is well documented, the process is well documented,
then each task should be very easy to put as a skill.
Yes, that's right.
Yeah. Absolutely.
No, no, no — absolutely not.
The only thing I would add to that is: how
can you be sure that the system is indeed well written?
And that's the part where I would say, okay, well, even if it's the human —
you can try.
Yeah. You just make sure to evaluate it.
So it goes back to that context development lifecycle —
like, something that we've done in this outreach where I help
improve the skills of some folks is we've created a GitHub Action.
So an automation for whenever somebody
improves their skill in open source, it triggers these evaluations.
And so that becomes part of their CI.
It just becomes part of their workflows.
So if the skills are
dependent on the model that you're using and that has been tested,
we keep it like a catalog or metadata — or this:
"this skill has been optimized under these conditions."
And I mean, or even in the same markdown
file, with some comments.
Yeah, I would say two answers to that.
The first one — this is why versioning is very important.
And the second one is yeah, this is where also the governance of the skill,
based on the convention, policy and practices of the team, matters.
So if your team believes that our skill works well because of X, Y,
Z — it's been evaluated and for some reason you'd like to use XYZ model —
perhaps Haiku, because it's a smaller model,
it will be cheaper and it works for this use case —
then you have merit to continue doing it like this.
But if another team within the organization has,
for the sake of argument, a bigger budget, and they want to make sure they use
frontier models, they can evaluate your skill against Opus 4.7
and then they're going to have some sort of findings.
Your skill works just as well.
Or maybe actually,
for this exact evaluation criteria for these scenarios that we care about,
we want to actually leverage this different model.
Well, actually, you know what?
I'm just going to make a different skill.
And so yours continues to run alongside for your process,
while the other team is going to do that as well.
It could be also a scenario where both of you are using the same skill,
and just the different versions of the skills are outdated.
And so I think the core takeaway here is:
models are non-deterministic, and we are trying
to figure out a way to bring a little bit of engineering back to it.
And if we take anything from DevOps and test-driven development, it's that
actually there is a path
where you can evaluate what you feed and what you get out of it.
I think that's — that's the key thing here.
Does that make sense?
Yes. I have
one question.
Well, we'll get to them at the end if that's okay.
Okay. So going back to it.
How do you enable your team to develop context and upskill now?
So, three approaches.
First one — give it a spin by yourself tonight.
Open up the terminal.
Give it a try.
Play with it.
And you have a good feel at a personal level
of what that actually means once you do that as a developer.
Within Tessl, we have a community called AI Native Dev.
So the AI Native Dev blog — we write extensively about this,
and we try to make analysis
about the latest models that come out and how that relates to skills and context.
But on a —
if I take a step back, the way you enable your team to work with agents is going
to be very different at a manager level, at a team level, or at a VP level.
So I'm not going to spend too much time going through all of these.
But if you want to take a moment to just perhaps take a picture of this, I think
this is the sort of framework we think of when thinking about what roles —
how those different roles should be —
thinking about things based on the context development lifecycle
of generating context, testing that context, distributing,
and then observing and then going back to the generation.
Now, the last way —
we have — so this community — we have the AI Native Dev,
we've organised — we are organising a conference
that's happening on June 1st and 2nd in London.
This is a community- first event, very practitioner-led.
There's going to be a lot of talks and actual
coding exercises for you to really get your hands dirty into it.
And the four initial problems I laid out at the beginning
are going to be sort of the key thematics of this conference.
So on the "we don't know how to build with agents yet" — we'll have focus on OpenAI.
We'll have the CTO of Netlify, folks from Meta, on how to be like
an AI native developer. On the "we can't verify generated code" —
we have the ex-CTO of Docker, we have the VP of product from Base and Cisco.
Like, how do you leverage specs — spec-driven development —
with context, on "AI writes code faster?"
Then we can coordinate —
the founder of Tessl, who's also the founder of Snyk —
who will be discussing how skills are the new code.
We'll have distinguished engineer Birgitta Böckeler from ThoughtWorks and,
you know, the very own Patrick Debois coming to share his latest thoughts.
And on the security front, like —
you know, "your AI is the new attack surface" — we'll have folks from Snyk,
the head of DevRel from Gemini CLI, and also focus on GitHub security.
So this is an event because
we want to educate the space and also try to figure things out altogether.
Nobody has the end solution yet, but we believe this has like
really quality speakers from very senior positions.
So you can scan the QR code.
It has a discount code.
It will knock off a little bit of the pricing directly.
Now, to close up on this conversation and give you practical takeaways
or things to think about as you get back on your way:
the SDLC — software development lifecycle — is changing.
We believe that it's now
the rise of the context development lifecycle.
One of the ways we believe
this — the key pillar of this — is thinking of test-
driven development and having evaluations be part of your workflow.
As mentioned,
we are thinking of these evaluations of skills — structure and activation — versus
actually pressure testing
your skills.
For managing —
engineering managers, VPs, team leads — whether you're managing 50
or 2,000 engineers, it's an agent enablement problem.
If this is on your roadmap, have a chat with me after, or go on
Tessl.io.
A cost-saving opportunity
is something that I invite folks to look into.
Maybe you can use a skill with a lower model.
That's what the data is signalling to us.
And finally, code is the artifact and context is the asset.
So if I'm wrong about anything, I'll see you on Reddit again.
Thank you.